MASHA AYUB WANJE

80113 - Mariakani, Mombasa | Kwale County | +254 707 979 411 | +254 754 054 015 ayub.wanje@gmail.com

Portfolio: wanjez.vercel.app

Computing and Analysis Skills

CAREER A resourceful with vast experience in IT, database management skills, web

PROFILE: development skills, SEO optimization, Rest API development & management, a critical

and analytical thinker with an inclination to observing organizational guidelines and

objectives.

I have 7 + years in web development, have good communication and leaderships

skills, am self-driven and motivated towards building systems and training.

PLATFORM & FRAMEWORKS:

Windows OS, NodeJS, ReactJS, NextJS, jQuery, Ajax, Spring Boot, REST Api, GraphQL

APPLICATIONS &

TOOLS:

NetBeans, Visual Studio, Workbench, Eclipse IDE, Sublime Text, IntelliJ IDEA, Git,

NPM, Docker

LANGUAGES: Java, Javascript, Python

MARKUP & STYLING:

HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Framer Motion

DATABASE SYSTEMS: MySOI

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, H2

SYSTEM SECURITY:

JWT, OAuth2, Spring Security

CLOUD TECH:

AWS, GCP, AZURE

SERVERS:

Tomcat, Xamp, Wamp

BACKEND TESTING:

Postman, Imeter

FRONTEND TESTING:

Selenium, Cypress, Jest

PROTOTYPING &

DESIGN

Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

Experience

Thermax Global LTD. (Vipingo Industries)

Fullstack Developer

Feb 2024 - Present

- Design and develop Maintenance Management Platform using react js.
- Developing tests for Maintenance Management Platform using jest.
- Maintaining code base for HSE platform (backend) using NodeJS using GitHub

Devki Steel Mills (Samburu, Msa)

Snr Backend Engineer (Power Plant)

July 2019 to Jan 2024

- Designing and development of an Inventory management system for Power Plant using ReactJS
- Developing a reactive power calculation platform for energy and power tracking using NextJS
- Liaising with Instrumentation team in maintenance of servers and UPS systems. Supervise IT team in maintenance of systems
- Developing a Task management and tracking system for maintenance and electrical teams using Spring Boot for backend and ReactJS for frontend
- Maintaining all code bases with Git

Kenya Coast National Polytechnic

Part - Time Trainer

March 2017 to June 2019

ICT Diploma Class of 2017 (Module III)

- Graphic Design fundamentals (Photoshop)
- Database systems and management (SQL)
- Front End Development best practices
- Scripting fundamental with Javascript
- Final Year Project mentoring

Electrical Diploma Class of 2017 (Module I & II)

- Engineering Mathematics
- Electrical Measurements and Fault diagnosis
- ICT Fundamentals

Nelmasoft ltd

Fullstack Web Developer

2015 - 2018

- Developed responsive and interactive websites and web applications using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Built Scalable and efficient backend systems using Nodejs, Express, MongoDB and MySQL
- Conducted code reviews and provided constructive feedback to colleagues to ensure a standardized team productivity and code quality.
- Stayed up to date with the latest web development trends and technologies, incorporating best practices and optimizations into projects to enhance user experience and performance.

Education

Technical University of Mombasa (Sept. 2009 - Nov. 2016)
Bachelor's Degree in Electrical and Electronics Engineering
- Relevant Coursework: - Software Development (Java, C++)

Ribe Boys High School (2004 - 2007) Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Stephen Kanja Primary School (1995- 2003) Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

Referees

Gwama Mvurya, Solutions Specialist | Product Manager, KCB Bank, gwama.mvurya@gmail.com, 0726535075

Amos Chengo, CEO, Mosmos Tech. | Nelmasoft Ltd. mashachengojr@gmail.com 0713124436

Francis Njuguna, ICT HOD, Kenya Coast National Polytechnic, mynjuguna@gmail.com, 0714822855